Kolby Kiernan

Front End Engineer | Sales Engineer

Anaheim, California, 92808 | (714) 746-4611 kolbykiernan@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

SUMMARY

Software enthusiast with a versatile background in both sales and software engineering. As a former Sales Manager and Account Executive in the software industry, I've honed my communication, leadership, and problem-solving skills in collaborative environments. While I am capable of handling full stack development, my expertise and passion lie in front-end development, specifically with React libraries, and sales engineering, where I have consistently excelled.

PROGRAMMING SKILLS

- HTML / CSS
- Sass / Bootstrap / Tailwind
- JavaScript / Typescript
- AWS / Deployment

- Node / Express
- React / Redux
- React Native / Expo Go
- Python3

- PostgreSQL / SQL
- Appwrite
- Mongoose / MongoDB
- Cybersecurity

WORK EXPERIENCE

<u>The Nest</u> - Built with: React.js, Express.js, Node.js, PostgreSQL, React-Bootstrap - <u>See Video Demo Here</u> *Full Stack Engineer:* February 2024 - present

A web application designed to improve the experience of creating and managing a wedding guest list by categorizing and assigning values to potential guests, then comparing that to desired attendance counts and venue capacity. This mobile-friendly app allows users to create profiles to manage their personal data. This app exemplifies the use of virtual DOM manipulation, reusable components, JSX syntax, state management, prop-drilling, hooks, and localStorage usage. The next iteration will use the inputted data to return a mock seating chart. I am responsible for every aspect of the build.

Boulevard Labs - "The first and only software client experience platform for appointment-based, self-care businesses."

Sales Engineering Responsibilities: Jan 2023 - Jan 2024

- Listening and Empathizing: Collaborated with small businesses to address concerns and ensure shared goals were met, increasing client retention amongst churn risks by 8% and new business close rate at 15% YoY in 2023.
- Understanding Technical & Business Needs: Gained deep understanding of software intricacies and effort required for feature implementation, identifying when to involve technical teams, and delivered decisions to prospects/customers.
- Finding Efficient Solutions: Identified and proposed least time-consuming solutions, often avoiding unnecessary feature builds, saving 11% in development time.

Account Executive: July 2021 - Jan 2024

- **Spearheaded** the entire sales lifecycle, from lead generation and prospecting to closing high-value contracts, consistently exceeding sales targets by an average of 25%.
- Secured over 100 new logos and generated \$1,000,000+ in annual recurring revenue (ARR), significantly contributing to Boulevard Labs' transition from Series B to Series C funding, which resulted in a 50% increase in company valuation.
- Achieved and surpassed 100% of sales quota for Q2, Q3, Q4 in 2022, while earning recognition as the top Account Executive in the recruitment class for exemplary performance.

Gallo Wine Co - "A family company that will remain the global wine industry leader, and continue to win new friends for wine."

District Manager: June 2019 - July 2021

OTHER PROJECTS

Aora - Built with: React Native, Expo Go, NativeWind, Animatable, Appwrite

A mobile application that mimics the basics of Instagram and Tik Tok. This sleek and modern app allows users to create profiles, view shared videos, upload content from their mobile phones, bookmark 'favorites', and join the community of digital content sharing.

Rest-Rant - Built with: React.js, Express.js, Node.js, MongoDB

A web application that mimics the basics of Yelp, focusing on RESTful APIs and CRUD operations. This mobile-friendly app allows users to add a restaurant and general information, leave comments or ratings, and make edits and deletions.

EDUCATION

San Diego State University

Software Development Certification, Computer Software Engineering: July 2023 - May 2024 Bachelor of Arts in Economics: August 2013 - December 2017